

Chie Hayashida

Software engineer with extensive knowledge of **DWH** architectures, **ML** pipelines and infrastructure engineering. Designed and Developed many types of systems which includes both BtoB and BtoC systems in **9+ years** of experience. Combines **technical** skills, creativity and leadership to empower the business from an engineering point of view. Has excellent presentation skills and self motivative enough to learn new technologies, contribute to **OSS** and write technical articles.

Work experience

12/2019 - PRESENT TOKYO, JAPAN

Strategic Cloud Engineer(Data & Analytics) Google

- * Leads and consult on **data migration** from onpremises and AWS to GCP, **DWH development** and **MLOps** projects.
- * Develops **Dataflow** modules for Hive to BigQuery migration.
- * Creates some external and internal assets such as **GCP blogs** and **guidelines**.
- * **Gives feedback and discusses** about customer requests with the product team.
- * Created an internal tool for GCP capacity planning for customer usage

11/2017 - 11/2020 TOKYO

Software Engineer Cookpad.Inc

- Leads the development of search and recommendation for Cookpad itself and new businesses in all processes of designing and evaluating KPI, make and managing strategic plans, implementation, in terms of NLP and machine learning.
- Develops tools to simplify machine learning deployment and maintenance.
- Builds AutoML function using table data for recipe data normalization.
- Makes technical presentations at several conferences and write technical articles for recruitment and awareness improvement.

12/2018 - 01/2019 TOKYO

Freelance Engineer Ubie.Inc

 Built ChatOps System for Kubernetes deployment with Golang.

Work experience

03/2017 - 10/2017 TOKYO

Data Engineer Retty.Inc

- Launched and led the data engineering team and solved problems of current DWH.
- Built the basis of data utilization environment using Apache Spark, BigQuery, fluentd, kinesis, Airflow and embulk in a short period of time.
- Led infrastructure configuration management in AWS and GCP environments using **Terraform** and **Ansible**.

04/2010 - 04/2017 TOKYO

Software Engineer NTT Data Corporation

- Designed and developed data processing and recommender algorithms for the TV program recommendation system using Hadoop and Spark (global system, 4000+ nodes).
- Conducted PoC of data processing for exhaustion prediction of car parts using sensor data.
- Contributed to Apache Hadoop, Apache Spark,
 Apache Airflow, and so on
- Designed and implemented data transfer, backup and recovery procedures with a performance-oriented approach, in the BCP project of a huge and demanding mobile fee sustem.
- Took charge of everything from network, OS to middleware design for system development in the US of a Japanese company.
- Performed root cause analysis in response to a technical troubleshooting request for Hadoop and Spark from a customer with a support contract.
- Did troubleshooting about **Oracle Database** in several projects.
- **Educated** and mentored several engineers.

Education

04/2008 - 03/2010 NARA, JAPAN

MSc Engineering Nara Institute of Science and Technology

- Master thesis described Linear transformation approaches to many-to-one voice conversion.
- We made 8+ presentations at domestic conferences and study groups.

04/2004 - 03/2008 OSAKA, JAPAN

BSc EngineeringOsaka University

- Learned about programming basics(C and C++), biotechnology, mathematical analysis, linear algebra, statistics, and mechanical engineering.
- Bachelor thesis described Measurement method of receptive field characteristics of primary visual cortex.

★ Skills

- # Hadoop # Spark # TensorFlow
- # Elasticsearch # Kubernetes # Solr
- # Distributed Computing
- # Big Data processing # Machine Learning
- # Recommender Systems
- # Information Retrieval # NLP # Analytics
- # Operating Systems(Unix, Windows)
- # Python # Scala # Golang # Java
- # C++ # Cloud Computing
- # Oracle Database # Project Management
- # R&D # Leadership # Decision making

R Languages





Certificates

12/2020

Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer Google

10/2018

AWS Solution Architect Associate AWS

04/2012

Database Specialist IPA

Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification

Certificates

Scheme

10/2012

Network Specialist

Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification Scheme

04/2011

Applied Information Technology Engineer

Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification Scheme

Achievements

- Won 1st prize in micro service tuning contest at AWS re:Invent2018 GameDay.
- Won 18th prize (Top 1%) in one week challenge at Kaggle PetFinder competition.
- A contributor and reviewer of TensorFlow document translation and ci tools of it.
- Develop and contributes some OSS includes
 TensorFlow, Apache Spark and so on.
- **A (co-)organizer** of several communities and meetups in Tokyo.
- Performed speeches at PyConJP, PyData London, Docker Meetup and so on.
- Writing technical articles in Gihyo Magagines.

Hobbies

IoT, DIY, 3D printing



Traveling





Piano